Last week we built once a game in with
one prompt with Opus 4.8. Yesterday
Fable 5 launched and now what we are we
are going to build a full a native
gaming studios.
>> With one prompt.
>> With maybe two.
>> Maybe two.
>> So if you want to see what Fable 5 is
capable of, watch this video.
>> The coding is Fable already. Here it
makes you think of a game, right?
>> I mean
>> It's a perfect name.
>> I mean for for sure. Like for sure.
>> Game studio AI.
>> Yes. Did you play Fable on Xbox when it
>> [laughter]
>> No, I didn't. I think I did it like once
or so, but I I can't even remember, so.
>> What we have done last week was that.
>> Yes. But this is cool. You have actually
a working game already.
>> A nice video.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah, we left it over with the same
pieces all together. We put like we
prompted like a couple of times after,
but now
>> You made some upgrades.
>> Yeah, automatically. Okay. So the way I
did it was I got another account and
then I run it on automation. Like every
hours, two hours and four hours because
then it was taking too much token. So I
every four hours I had a GitHub board
with all of the features and all of the
direction that I wanted and now welcome
to Ship [__] Games.
>> Yeah, just to tell people that you did
this with your own skills, your own
prompts and your own automation to to
optimize everything. It is not a one
shot at game.
>> Yeah, I know exactly. Yeah, it's it's
basically like since last week auto
automations, loops and verification for
the asset and stuff. It's not like 100%
done yet, but it's getting there. So we
have a website. We have 200 commits 200
commits in 30 days. I also have a
building public Git tracker now. It's
connected to GitHub and it tracks all of
the commits.
>> Okay, that's cool.
>> I didn't build seven games, one game but
seven. Production sprites, okay, that's
nice. Like for the weapon and stuff like
that. And ships 200 130 here, okay. So,
seven games, I'm going to show you all
of them after that. But yeah, scores
game deadline, which is like a top
defender. Pack four, which is like a
mobile jewels stuff. Star light, it's
like a not space invader, it's arcades
game stuff. Like a fight
when you shoot and then you move and
stuff like that. Redline, which is it's
like a Sonic alternative, Sonic
Hedgehog. You just run the map and
because you have a messenger to deliver
blah blah. Worth, I don't remember which
is one. The platform. Yeah, no, it's
Super Mario.
>> Oh, cool.
>> So, yeah, I want to I want to try
different game style and see which one
is like the easier to to implement. And
the war lane is table commander slash
maps and it's a hobby for because it's
will be all of that will be multiplayer
because why not? And it's a map with the
war and stuff. Yeah.
>> And that's why you make it more
difficult, right? Because a multiplayer
is not just a one shot a game that runs
locally.
>> Yeah, I mean, you know, like I I define
a scope and then it's oh yeah, I have a
new idea, let's build that. Let's see
where it goes. So, play dead road,
that's the game. And obviously,
everything is open source. So, if you
want to check how we did that, check all
of the links, the skills, the games
itself, all of the repository,
everything is free. And it's also based
on your on the skills that we have and
like the ship sheet dev V0 template.
Everything is a mono repo, so everything
is accessible and public. And if you
want to pay us, you can buy a studio
pass 99 99 dollars [laughter]
>> You're lucky, only $29.
>> Yeah, exactly. And yeah, also clean
clean clean content because we can with
a bit luck. And a gallery, the second
website is dead roads, which is the game
by itself. And I'm going to the same
thing like with the law and stuff. I'm
going to talk about the law too because
that's going to be interesting. But
first, demo of the game. so we are going
into war lane. It's going to be loud
because that's a doom like design mood
reduced sound. So we have a common
stable where your strategy base stuff is
like resources that will impact all of
those games. With like I'm going to show
you the FPS first because that's the
most built-in game. So sketch survivor
player run. You can choose your
character. There is different weapons, a
gun, shotgun, a SMG and sniper.
>> I'm going to try with that shotgun. That
would be fun. And now we are back on the
map.
>> Oh.
>> They explode. There is loud. There is
like some members and stuff. And that's
the bonus. So you improving your
>> Yes, yeah. Your abilities.
>> Yes, exactly. Abilities are doing the
game. That player run. I'm going to try
with another one. And now we have
another weapon and it's a SMG. Back
Okay, that's the game. Okay, I'm going
to back to the I'm going to go back to
the lobby. Okay, so star blood. That the
playing game. You're going to see it
away. So I'm a plane and then there is
like some space invaders coming and then
I'm shooting them. And same thing like
same gaming loop. You have abilities and
you get you improve them. That's it.
That's the game.
>> I'm I'm wondering if I should like do it
like a 3D, but I'm curious about the
sprites that are
>> That makes it difficult.
>> Yeah. Main menu path. War lane. Okay, so
star blood. We did it. Back for Yeah,
see that for example like the sprite is
bleeding on the right and because it's
one band and it should only display one
image.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> That's the MOBA. Okay, that was one
prompt of office 4.8. That's supposed to
be like a League of Legend, but not here
yet.
>> It It needs some modifications.
>> So dead lane. Okay, back path deploy. Oh
yeah, that's the tower defense. It's
sick. So I'm building a a tower and then
>> Tower defense game.
>> Yes. And And the first prompt was like a
3D views. The game works. [__] works.
And I can't I've gold so I can rebuild
the tower again with more and it's going
to be I I think this one is going to be
is going to be amazing. Like Okay,
that's it.
>> That's cool.
>> Yeah, it's nice. The public repository
ship ship games dead road and the skill
and everything is a mono repo which for
dead road we have all of the games in
app/games but we have the law which is
an obsidian vault with only markdown
files and I can So what I do is I write
the law like the story the tier etc. And
then all of the games are attached to
the law.
>> So that means that every game is playing
in the same world.
>> Exactly. That's the same universe. Yeah,
the obsidian vault. So yeah, I haven't
like the design. I have like the design
MD file that will be consistent with
everything all of the games all of the
universe is based on that. So I will
probably like change it along the way
but like everything And because it's a
mono repo then the agent has the context
of that all the time and I it should at
least refer to it all the time.
>> Yeah, yeah. I get almost the same
styling and
>> Exactly. And then I can always like
yeah, go back to a refer yourself to the
the vault check yeah, like the game what
we define for the game problem law the
goals you want format win condition.
It's it's just nuts. And then you
iterate on top of that again and again
and again for weeks months and then you
have a cool Mario Party Doom like game.
Yeah, so everything is extracted to
build for that games in a ship ship game
stuff but like the engine to build all
of the sprite or like to animate the
monster in the game can works in other
game and like you said yeah, if people
wants to use that CLI or those
integration etc. They can to generate
their own sprite and for their own
stuff.
>> Yeah, I think it's a good start. You can
use it as a basis.
>> Exactly. And I also have like resources,
which is some YouTube channel that I've
dropped the YouTube link and it extract
the transcript. And by doing that, I
have everything that I talk about. And
if there is any rules that I need to
know to build the games, then I can drop
it and read the transcript and I create
the next tool on stuff like that.
>> Yeah, and I saw up to AI oriented dev.
Like I love his channel.
>> It's It's It's going to be us later on.
>> I love his channel. Like it's really
cool. And he's making He's making a lot
of views. Like his fighter games,
amazing. Look Look at the name.
>> This is good. This is not This is
awesome quality.
>> Yeah. Like it's it's like it's frame
perfect. It's It's awesome. And it it
does like crazy. Whereas the same tools
that we have. And one technique that I
learned from his transcript is to For
example, for an animation, instead of
generate sprites from image to image,
you generate a video and then you
extract the frame of the animation.
>> Then it's always the exact same styling.
>> Exactly. And it's not bleeding from one
to another. It's just going to be a bit
more expensive to generate. So, yeah,
that's a problem. You can drop the tools
that he they they use and drop it to
Fable and to like copy paste and web
coding the same process. I love it.
>> Nice. We're going good way.
>> Nice.
>> Now we just need to be able to split it.
>> Yeah. Yeah, but then like it's just
Yeah, that's that's lit. But like Okay,
see that for example, it should never do
that because it's out of frame. So, that
should not happen.
>> Yeah. You have good results. Now it's
just optimizing.
>> Sprite from directive, let me check.
Nice. Nice. Nice. Love it.
>> Love it.
>> Let it go and see what it does.
>> Yes. Should we do like a series of live
slash video about how to how we progress
with that?
>> Oh yeah, that's cool.
>> Yeah, like it.
>> We even just small follow up, but just
let's go where and see let people see
what we are doing next.
>> Exactly. And uh hopefully have some
revenue because people will buy
>> the awesome skills.
>> description. And uh yeah, everyone
subscribe to the channel. Thanks for
watching the video. And play our games.
Bye.